let quiz = {
    chapter: 'Human Reproduction',
    topics: [
        'Male Repro System',
        'Female Repro System',
        'Gametogenesis',
        'Menstrual Cycle',
        'Fertilizing',
        'Implantation',
        'Pregnancy',
        'Embryonic Development',
        'Parturition',
        'Lactation',
    ],
    title: 'Human Reproduction Ex1',
    colors: ['#096c86', '#096c8636', '#dbf6fb'],
    questions: [
        {
            question: 'Animals which give birth to young ones are called:',
            options: ['amphibious ', 'oviparous', 'juveniles ', 'viviparous'],
            answer: 4,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question:
                'All of the following are functions of the sertoli cells in the seminiferous tubules except',
            options: [
                'they secrete an androgen-binding protein into the seminiferous tubule in response to FSH stimulation.',
                'they secrete inhibin, which exerts a negative feedback effect on the pituitary gland to inhibit FSH secretion.',
                'they secrete mullerian-duct stimulating hormone during embryonic sexual differentiation, which results in the development of the ductus deferens.',
                'they provide support for developing spermatozoa.',
            ],
            answer: 3,
            solution:
                'The sertoli cell mechanically supports developing sperm and produces androgen-binding protein, inhibin, and mullerian duct inhibitor, which causes regression of the mullerian duct system.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'A sperm cell moving from the lumen of the seminiferous tubule to the exterior of the body passes through all of the following structures except the',
            options: [
                'seminal vesicle ',
                'epididymis',
                'ductus deferens ',
                'urethra',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution:
                'The structures through which a sperm passes from the testis to the exterior include the epididymis, ductus deferens, ejaculatory duct, prostatic urethra, membranous urethra, and penile urethra. The secretions of the prostate gland empty into the prostatic urethra; the secretions of the seminal vesicles empty into the ejaculatory duct; and the secretions of the bulbourethral glands empty into the penile urethra.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'During embryonic development the heart beat begins at the end of',
            options: [
                '1st trimester ',
                '2nd trimester',
                '1st month ',
                '2nd month',
            ],
            answer: 3,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which of the following best represents the normal path of a sperm cell as it makes its way from the point of entry into the female’s reproductive tract to the place where fertilization typically occurs?',
            options: [
                'Cervix, vagina, ovary, oviduct',
                'Vagina, cervix, uterus, oviduct',
                'Uterus, cervix, vagina, oviduct',
                'Vagina, uterus, cervix, oviduct',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution:
                'A sperm is ejected by the male into the vagina. From the vagina the sperm move through the cervix into the uterus and finally the oviduct where fertilization occurs.',
        },
        {
            question: 'The function of the seminal vesicle is to',
            options: [
                'produce a solution of fructose to provide energy for the mitochondria of the sperm.',
                'secrete alkaline fluids that neutralize the acidity of the female’s reproductive tract.',
                'initiate the muscular contractions leading to emission.',
                'produce prostaglandins that stimulate contractions of the male reproductive organs.',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution:
                'The seminal vesicles are involved in producing the seminal fluid. One of the components of the seminal fluid is an energy source for the sperm in the form of fructose.',
        },
        {
            question: 'Part of sperm involved in penetrating egg membrane is –',
            options: ['Tail ', 'Acrosome', 'Allosome ', 'Autosome'],
            answer: 2,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question: 'The head of mature mammalian sperm is made of:',
            options: [
                'An acrosome',
                'Elongated nucleus covered by acrosome',
                'Two centrioles and an axial filament',
                'Nucleus, acrosome, cytoplasm and mitochondrial sheath',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question: 'The fertilization in human occurs at the junction of',
            options: [
                'Infundibulum and ampulla',
                'Isthmus and fundus',
                'Ampulla and isthmus',
                'Cervix and fundus',
            ],
            answer: 3,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which part of sperm provides energy it to fertilize the egg?',
            options: ['Sperm head ', 'Acrosome', 'Sperm tail ', 'Middle piece'],
            answer: 4,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which of the following is an example of positive feedback control in the reproductive cycle of males or females?',
            options: [
                'The increased response of the hypothalamus and anterior pituitary gland in response to estrogen.',
                'The decreased response of the hypothalamus and anterior pituitary gland in response to estrogen.',
                'The inhibition of luteinizing hormone by high levels of testosterone.',
                'The stimulation of luteinizing hormone by low levels of testosterone.',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution:
                'During day 12 to14, a positive feedback occurs in response to estrogen. The hypothalamus and anterior pituitary gland are stimulated to release LH and FSH.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which one of the following is not a biological or medical reality for human reproduction?',
            options: [
                'Negative feedback control of the hypothalamus by sex hormone.',
                'Contraception through complete chemical blockage of sperm production.',
                'Surgical transfer of gametes from one area of the reproductive tract to another.',
                'Susceptibility of reproductive organs to cancer.',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution:
                'Males are constantly making sperms so that any chemical block of sperm production would have to be constant. Chemical blocks of sperm would also have serious medical side effects.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Mature mammalian sperm are stored in the ____ prior to their release during ejaculation.',
            options: [
                'seminiferous tubules',
                'scrotum',
                'vas deferens',
                'epididymis',
            ],
            answer: 4,
            solution:
                'Located on the surface of each testis, the epididymis stores mature sperm until they are ready to be emitted just prior to ejaculation.',
        },
        {
            question: 'The function of the prostate gland in human males is to',
            options: [
                'initiate the muscular contractions leading to emission.',
                'initiate the muscular contractions leading to ejaculation.',
                'swell with blood and cause the penis to become erect.',
                'secrete alkaline fluids that neutralize the acidity of the female’s reproductive tract.',
            ],
            answer: 4,
            solution:
                'The woman’s reproductive tract is acidic to help protect against infection by microorganisms. Unfortunately, this environment is also hostile to the sperm. The prostate gland secretions are alkaline, which helps neutralize the pH of the female’s system and permits the sperm to survive longer.',
        },
        {
            question: 'FSH in males',
            options: [
                'Stimulates the Leydig cells for the secretion of testosterone',
                'Induces the appearance of secondary sexual characters',
                'Acts on sertoli cells that help in spermiogenesis',
                'Is also known as ICSH',
            ],
            answer: 3,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Secretions from which one of the following are rich in fructose, calcium and some enzymes?',
            options: [
                'Male accessory glands',
                'Liver',
                'Pancreas',
                'Salivary glands',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question: '‘Spermiogenesis’ refers to',
            options: [
                'Formation of spermatids',
                'Metamorphosis of spermatids into sperms',
                'Phase of multiplication of spermatogenesis',
                'Growth phase of spermatogenesis',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Assume 2n = 12 in a hypothetical species. In gametogenesis, the number of chromosomes in a spermatid would be __________ and in a first polar body would be __________',
            options: ['3, 6 ', '3, 3', '6, 3 ', '6, 6'],
            answer: 4,
            solution:
                'Haploid sex cells contain half as many chromosomes as diploid somatic cells.',
        },
        {
            question: 'The acrosome of the sperm is',
            options: [
                'the nucleus, containing highly condensed chromatin.',
                'located in the midpiece, where it supplies ATP for movement.',
                'the flagellum that makes up the sperm tail.',
                'a vesicle containing enzymes to help the sperm penetrate the egg.',
            ],
            answer: 4,
            solution:
                'The head of the sperm is tipped with a special body, the acrosome, which contains enzymes that help the sperm penetrate the egg.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'The tightly convoluted tubule that lies along the posterior surface of the testis is',
            options: [
                'the seminiferous tubule',
                'the rete testis',
                'the epididymis',
                'the ductus deferens',
            ],
            answer: 3,
            solution:
                'The epididymis is comma-shaped mass of threadlike tubules attached to the posterior border of a testis.',
        },
        {
            question: 'Cortical granules are associated with',
            options: [
                'Oogenesis ',
                'Spermatogenesis',
                'Cleavage ',
                'Fertilization',
            ],
            answer: 4,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question: 'Cowper’s glands are found in:',
            options: [
                'Female amphibians',
                'Male mammals',
                'Female mammals ',
                'Male amphibians',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which of the following statements about oogenesis is false?',
            options: [
                'The polar bodies degenerate after the second meiotic division.',
                'The ovum produced is haploid.',
                'The major growth phase of the primary oocyte occurs in prophase-I.',
                'The primary oocyte is haploid.',
            ],
            answer: 4,
            solution:
                'During oogenesis, the primary oocyte is diploid; after the first meiotic division into the secondary oocyte the cell becomes haploid.',
        },
        {
            question: 'The LH surge from the anterior pituitary gland',
            options: [
                'occurs just prior to ovulation.',
                'occurs just prior to menstruation.',
                'stimulates an estrogen surge from the ovaries.',
                'is responsible for follicle development in the uterus.',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution:
                'The LH surge is a peak burst of LH from the anterior pituitary gland, which causes ovulation. It occurs in the middle of the ovarian cycle and is stimulated by the positive feedback of a high blood level of estrogen that is sustained for 48 to 50 hours. Although FSH and LH stimulate follicle development at the beginning of a cycle, it is the LH surge that results in the rupture of the dominant follicle from the ovary.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'All of the following occur during natural menopause except',
            options: [
                'the number of ovarian follicles is reduced and eventually depleted.',
                'estrogen levels in the blood decrease.',
                'progesterone levels in the blood decrease.',
                'FSH and LH levels in the blood decrease.',
            ],
            answer: 4,
            solution:
                'Menopause is the cessation of menstrual cycles. It is caused by the depletion of ovarian follicles that started before birth and continues throughout the reproductive life of the female. In the absence of follicular development, the decreased estrogen and progesterone levels in the blood do not inhibit the pituitary FSH and LH levels and the cycles stop. The FSH and LH levels, however, remain high in the post-menopause.',
        },
        {
            question: 'Cleavage in the fertilized egg of humans:',
            options: [
                'Starts in uterus',
                'Is meroblastic',
                'Starts when egg is in fallopian tube',
                'Is discoidal',
            ],
            answer: 3,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question: 'Polar body is produced during the formation of –',
            options: [
                'Sperm ',
                'Secondary oocyte',
                'Oogonium ',
                'Spermatocytes',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question: 'Which one is a primary sex organ?',
            options: ['Testis ', 'Scrotum', 'Prostate ', 'Penis'],
            answer: 1,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Withdrawal of which of the following hormones is the immediate cause of menstruation?',
            options: ['FSH ', 'FSH-RH', 'Progesterone ', 'Estrogen'],
            answer: 3,
            solution:
                'Progesterone hormone which is secreted by the corpus luteum in the ovaries is responsible to stop ovulation (during pregnancy) and fixes the foetus to the uterine wall, facilitates placenta formation and controls the foetus development in uterus. If this hormone is withdrawn then fixation of foetus to uterine wall will not take place, formation of placenta will also not take place, ovulation starts from the ovaries and hence in human female menstruation starts.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'In the human female, menstruation can be deferred by the administration of',
            options: [
                'combination of FSH and LH',
                'combination of estrogen and progesterone',
                'FSH only',
                'LH only',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution:
                'The progesterone and estradiol continue the hypertrophy of endometrial lining in the uterus and fallopian tubes and maintain it throughout pregnancy. Progesterone is also necessary for the proper implantation of the foetus in the uterine wall. It stimulates the endometrial glands to secrete a nutrient fluid for the foetus, hence the term secetory phase. The progesterone inhibits the release of FSH so that it may not develop additional follicles and eggs.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'In humans, at the end of the first meiotic division, the male germ cells differentiate into the',
            options: [
                'primary spermatocytes',
                'secondary spermatocytes',
                'spermatids',
                'spermatozonia',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution:
                'In human, at the end of the first meiotic division, the male germ cells differentrate into the secondary spermatocytes.',
        },
        {
            question: 'Sertoli cells are found in',
            options: [
                'ovaries and secrete progesterone',
                'adrenal cortex and secrete adrenaline',
                'seminiferous tubules and provide nutrition to germ cells',
                'pancreas and secrete cholecystokinin',
            ],
            answer: 3,
            solution:
                'Sertoli cells are found in the walls of seminiferous tubules of the testes. They anchor and provide nutrition to the developing germ cells especially the spermatids.',
        },
        {
            question: 'Seminal plasma in human males is rich in:',
            options: [
                'fructose and calcium',
                'glucose and calcium',
                'DNA and testosterone',
                'ribose and potassium',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution:
                'Seminal plasma in human males are rich in fructose, calcium and certain enzymes. They provide a medium for transport of sperms, nourishes and activates sperms.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which accessory genital gland occurs only in mammalian male?',
            options: [
                'Prostate gland ',
                'Perineal gland',
                'Cowper’s gland ',
                'Bartholin gland',
            ],
            answer: 3,
            solution:
                'A bulbourethral gland (or Cowper’s gland) is one of two small exocrine glands present in the reproductive system of human males. They are homologous to Bartholin’s glands in females.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Oocyte is liberated from ovary under the influence of LH, after completing –',
            options: [
                'Mitosis and before liberating polar bodies',
                'Meiosis I and before liberating second polar bodies',
                'Meiosis',
                'Meiosis II after release of first polar body',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution:
                'Oocyte is liberated from ovary under the influence of LH,after completing meiosis I and before liberating secondpolar bodies.',
        },
        {
            question:
                '10 oogonia yield 10 primary oocytes, then how many ova are produced on completion of oogenesis –',
            options: ['5 ', '10', '20 ', '40'],
            answer: 2,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Keeping a normal, sexually mature woman in her mid-twenties on continuous high doses of progesterone will',
            options: [
                'cause her to ovulate repeatedly within each menstrual cycle.',
                'stimulate the production of mature follicles.',
                'prevent her from producing mature follicles and ovulating.',
                'cause the endometrial lining of her uterus to slough off.',
            ],
            answer: 3,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Phase of menstrual cycle in human that lasts for 7-8 days is:',
            options: [
                'Follicular phase ',
                'Ovulatory phase',
                'Luteal phase ',
                'Menstruation',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question:
                'The role of the corpus luteum and the hormones it produces ends',
            options: [
                'at the time of embryonic implantation in the uterus.',
                'with the formation of the placenta.',
                'during the second trimester of pregnancy.',
                'just prior to parturition.',
            ],
            answer: 3,
            solution:
                'The corpus luteum’s production of hormones is essential for the maintenance of early pregnancy. During the second trimester, however, the placenta becomes fully formed and takes over hormone production, leading to degeneration of the corpus luteum.',
        },
        {
            question: 'Egg is liberated from ovary in',
            options: [
                'Secondary oocyte stage',
                'Primary oocyte stage',
                'Oogonial stage',
                'Mature ovum stage',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question: 'Menstruation results in the discharge of',
            options: [
                'the corpus luteum of the uterus.',
                'surface cells from the vagina.',
                'blood from the outer surface of the uterus.',
                'the endometrial lining.',
            ],
            answer: 4,
            solution:
                'In menstrual cycles, the endometrium is shed from the uterus through the cervix and vagina.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'The ovary undergoes several structural changes or events during the human female’s menstrual cycle. Which one of the following sequences is correct, beginning with the oocyte?',
            options: [
                'Corpus luteum development -→ follicle development -→ ovulation',
                'Follicle development -→ ovulation -→ corpus luteum development',
                'Corpus luteum development -→ ovulation -→ follicle development',
                'Follicle development -→ corpus luteum development -→ ovulation',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution:
                'The ovarian cycle consists of a follicular phase, during which follicles grow to maturity, followed by ovulation. This is followed by a luteal phase during which the old follicle cells that were left behind form the corpus luteum.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Into which structure is a human oocyte released upon ovulation?',
            options: [
                'Fallopian tube ',
                'Ovary',
                'Abdominal cavity ',
                'Uterus',
            ],
            answer: 3,
            solution:
                'The female reproductive system is not completely closed, and the egg is released into the abdominal cavity near the opening of the oviduct.',
        },
        {
            question: 'Bartholin’s glands occurs in:',
            options: [
                'Females, and help in vestibular lubrication',
                'Females, and produce oestrogen for regulating secondary sexual characters.',
                'Males, and form liquid part of spermatic fluid',
                'Males, and produce alkaline fluid for neutralizing urethral acidity.',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question: 'The human placenta is formed from:',
            options: [
                'Amnion',
                'Yolk sac',
                'Allantois and chorion',
                'None of the above',
            ],
            answer: 3,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question:
                'At the end of first meiotic divisioin, male germ cell differentiates into',
            options: [
                'Secondary spermatocyte',
                'Primary spermatocyte',
                'Spermatogonium',
                'Spermatid',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which of the following is not part of the female external genitalia ?',
            options: ['Clitoris ', 'Vagina', 'Labia majora ', 'Labia minora'],
            answer: 2,
            solution:
                'The vagina is an internal reproductive organ and is not considered part of the vulva.',
        },
        {
            question: 'Menstruation is initiated by',
            options: [
                'a sudden release of FSH from the anterior pituitary.',
                'a lack of estrogens and progesterone due to degeneration of the corpus luteum.',
                'an increased release of estrogens and progesterone from the corpus luteum.',
                'a sudden drop in LH.',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution:
                'A decrease in estrogen and progesterone as the corpus luteum degenerates (in the absence of pregnancy) initiates menstruation.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'All of the following statements concerning pregnancy are accurate except',
            options: [
                'the detection of human chorionic gonadotropin in the urine forms the basis for pregnancy tests.',
                'the cyclic release of pituitary gonadotropins and ovarian steroids is continued.',
                'the mammary gland tissue of the pregnant woman is stimulated to develop by placental hormones.',
                'the corpus luteum of pregnancy maintains the uterus until the placenta is well established.',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution:
                'The high levels of estrogen and progesterone in the maternal circulation during pregnancy inhibit the cyclic release of pituitary gonadotropins and prevent the menstrual cycles. Pregnancy hormones include HCG, which maintains the corpus luteum of pregnancy and forms the basis for pregnancy diagnosis urine tests. Ovarian and placental estrogen and progesterone, human placental lactogen, and pituitary prolactin stimulate development of the ducts and alveoli in the mammary glands.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'At the time of fertilization sperm head enters in the egg from',
            options: [
                'Any where ',
                'Animal pole',
                'Vegetal pole ',
                'Lateral side of egg',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question: 'Which chemical of the eggs attracts and holds sperm ?',
            options: [
                'Fertilizin ',
                'Antifertilizin',
                'Agglutin ',
                'Antiagglutin',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which of the following organ is differentiated first during development?',
            options: ['Heart ', 'Skin', 'Brain ', 'Neural tube'],
            answer: 3,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question: 'The human embryo, with 8 to 16 blastomere is called',
            options: ['Morula ', 'Blastula', 'Gastrula ', 'Foetus'],
            answer: 1,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question:
                'A couple have been trying to conceive a child for over a year without success. Recently, the man’s doctor informed him that his seminal vesicles are defective. This means that',
            options: [
                'the man makes functional sperm, but they are not delivered because he is unable to ejaculate.',
                'the man’s sperm lack functional flagella',
                'the fluid needed to lubricate the man’s urethra for easier sperm travel is defective.',
                'the man’s semen lacks the fructose fuel needed for the sperm to swim.',
            ],
            answer: 4,
            solution:
                'Seminal vesicles produce the fructose sugars that power the sperm’s mitochondria.',
        },
        {
            question: 'Grey crescent is the area:',
            options: [
                'At the point of entry of sperm into ovum',
                'Just opposite to the site of entry of sperm into ovum',
                'At the animal pole',
                'At the vegetal pole',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question:
                'In the urinogenital organs of rabbit which one of following part is present in male but not in female?',
            options: ['Urethra ', 'Fallopian tube', 'Vagina ', 'Vas deferens'],
            answer: 4,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which of the following statements about human pregnancy and foetal development is false ?',
            options: [
                'The blastocyst is a stage in foetal development that appears early during the third trimester.',
                'A vital connection between the foetal and maternal blood supplies occurs at the placenta.',
                'Most of the growth in foetal size occurs during the second and third trimesters.',
                'All major organ systems have formed by the end of the foetus’s first three months of life.',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution:
                'The blastocyst is one of the very first stages in human embryonic development, occurring early in the first trimester.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'An important factor contributing to the onset and maintenance of labour contractions is',
            options: [
                'increased contractility of the uterine muscles from increased oxytocin levels.',
                'mechanical pressure on the cervix generated by the emerging baby’s head.',
                'stretching of the uterus during the final stages of foetal growth.',
                'All of the above',
            ],
            answer: 4,
            solution:
                'Labour is brought on and intensified by all of these factors.',
        },
        {
            question: 'Identical twins result when',
            options: [
                'the zygote divides and the daughter cells split and develop independently.',
                'two eggs with identical genetic material are fertilized, each by a different sperm.',
                'an embryo splits before cellular differentiation has occurred.',
                'Both A and C ',
            ],
            answer: 4,
            solution:
                'If an embryo splits before cell fate has been determined, identical twins may result.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which one of the following describes the correct sequence of stages during embryogenesis?',
            options: [
                'Blastula formation, cleavage, gastrulation',
                'Blastula formation, gastrulation, cleavage',
                'Cleavage, gastrulation, blastula formation',
                'Cleavage, blastula formation, gastrulation',
            ],
            answer: 4,
            solution:
                'The zygote initially undergoes cleavage until the blastula stage is reached. Gastrulation is a drammatic rearrangement of the cells of the blastula.',
        },
        {
            question: 'After which cell division Spermatogonia are formed?',
            options: ['Meiosis I ', 'Meiosis II', 'Mitosis ', 'Amitosis'],
            answer: 3,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question: 'In human adult females oxytocin:',
            options: [
                'causes strong uterine contraction during parturition',
                'is secreted by anterior pituitary',
                'stimulates growth of mammary glands',
                'stimulates pituitary to secrete vasopressin',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question: 'Gestation period is the duration between',
            options: [
                'Ovulation and fertilization',
                'Maturation of egg and ovulation',
                'Fertilization and parturition',
                'Ovulation and parturition',
            ],
            answer: 3,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which one of the following is the precise site of embryo implantation in a normal pregnancy ?',
            options: ['Endometrium ', 'Vagina', 'Oviduct ', 'Cervix'],
            answer: 1,
            solution:
                'This is the capillary-rich inner wall of the uterus, where implantation is accomplished for the developing human embryo.',
        },
        {
            question: 'Placenta is formed in humans by',
            options: ['amnion ', 'allantois', 'chorion ', 'All of these'],
            answer: 3,
            solution:
                'Human placenta is largely formed of chorion and contains blood vessels formed by allantois.',
        },
        {
            question: 'Cervix is a part',
            options: [
                'of kidney',
                'of fallopian tube',
                'of epididymis',
                'between uterus and vagina',
            ],
            answer: 4,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question: 'Structure connecting the foetus to placenta is',
            options: ['umbilical cord ', 'amnion', 'yolk sac ', 'chorion'],
            answer: 1,
            solution: ' ',
        },
        {
            question: 'Fertilization occur in',
            options: ['Uterus ', 'Ureter', 'Vagina ', 'Fallopian tube'],
            answer: 4,
            solution: '',
        },
        {
            question: 'The milk-ejection reflex is stimulated by',
            options: ['oxytocin ', 'estrogen', 'prolactin ', 'progesterone'],
            answer: 1,
            solution:
                'Prolactin stimulates the milk production and oxytocin stimulates the myoepithelial cells, which cause the milkejection reflex.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which extra-embryonic membrane in humans prevents desiccation of the embryo inside the uterus?',
            options: ['Chorion ', 'Allantois', 'Yolk sac ', 'Amnion'],
            answer: 4,
            solution:
                'Amnion is an extraembryonic membrane in human prevents desiccation of the embryo inside the uterus. Amnion is a membrane that encloses the embryo of reptiles, birds and mammals within the amniotic cavity. This cavity is filled with amniotic fluid, in which the embryo is protected from dessication and from external pressure.',
        },
        {
            question: 'Foetal ejection reflex in human female is induced by:',
            options: [
                'release oxytocin from pituitary',
                'fully developed foetus and placenta',
                'differentiation of mammary glands',
                'pressure exerted by amniotic fluid',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution:
                'Foetal ejection reflex in human female is induced by fully developed foetus and placenta. When a woman is in a lithotomy or semi-sitting position, the foetal ejection reflex is impaired and the increased pain caused by the sacrum’s inability to move as the baby descends can be untolerable.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'A change in the amount of yolk and its distribution in the egg will affect',
            options: [
                'pattern of cleavage',
                'number of blastomeres produced',
                'fertilization',
                'formation of zygote',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution:
                'A change in the amount of yolk and its distribution in the egg will affect pattern of cleavage. In eggs with less yolk, cleavages are equal, and the resulting blastomeres are of similar size. If the yolk is localized, such as in frog eggs, then clevages are unequal, the cells derived from the yolky region (the vegetal pole) are larger than those derived from the region without yolk (the animal pole).',
        },
        {
            question:
                'The first movements of the foetus and appearance of hair on its head are usually observed during which month of pregnancy?',
            options: [
                'Fourth month ',
                'Fifth month',
                'Sixth month ',
                'Third month',
            ],
            answer: 2,
            solution:
                'In human beings, after one month of pregnancy, the embryo’s heart is formed. By end of second month pregnancy, the foetus develops limbs and digits. By end of 12 weeks, major organ systems are formed. After fifth month, the first movement of foetus and appearance of hair on its head are observed. By the end of 24 weeks, the body is covered with hairs, eye lids separate and eyelashes are formed.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'If for some reason, the vasa efferentia in the human reproductive system gets blocked, the gametes will not be transported from',
            options: [
                'testes to epididymis',
                'epididymis to vas deferens',
                'ovary to uterus',
                'vagina to uterus',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution:
                'If the vasa efferentia in the human reproductive system get blocked the gametes will not be transformed from testes to epididymis.',
        },
        {
            question:
                'What happens during fertilisation in humans after many sperms reach close to the ovum?',
            options: [
                'Secretions of acrosome helps one sperm enter cytoplasm of ovum through zona pellucida',
                'All sperms except the one nearest to the ovum lose their tails',
                'Cells of corona radiata trap all the sperms except one',
                'Only two sperms nearest the ovum penetrate zona pellucida',
            ],
            answer: 1,
            solution: ' ',
        },
    ],
};
